<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHM | Feng, Jianshe</title>
    <link>/tag/phm/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/phm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PHM</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu2da6660f49e0ed3d134821ae9bbede5e_267278_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>PHM</title>
      <link>/tag/phm/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHM-enabled Maintenance Scheduling Optimization</title>
      <link>/project/3-phm-enabled-maintenance-scheduling-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/3-phm-enabled-maintenance-scheduling-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maintenance Scheduling and Routing (MS&amp;amp;R) is critical for the offshore wind farm to reduce maintenance cost. Although different models are proposed, the turbine operating conditions and the forecasted wind resources in the maintenance horizon are still less accounted in these current models. To address this issue, this research proposes a novel mathematical model to optimize the MS&amp;amp;R problem by highlighting the significance of turbine production loss (PL) before and during maintenance activities. In the proposed methodology, the PL term takes the most up-to-date wind turbine power curve and the forecasted wind resources as model inputs. Subsequently, a novel Genetic Algorithm (GA) solver is designed to minimize the PL of wind turbines together with the technician salaries and the transportation costs. The outcome of the proposed model gives a detailed maintenance plan with maintenance schedules, vessel routes, technician assignments, and cost breakdowns. Validation of the proposed model is implemented on real-world data collected from an offshore wind farm with several 4 MW wind turbines. The result demonstrates the effectiveness and superiority of the proposed method, and some practical findings are also summarized in the conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Virtual Metrology of Semiconductor Manufacturing Processes</title>
      <link>/project/1-online-virtual-metrology-of-semiconductor-manufacturing-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/1-online-virtual-metrology-of-semiconductor-manufacturing-processes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Metrology (VM) is an essential research for manufacturing processes, which aims to estimate the difficult-to-measure parameters of products or processes by computer programs. Modeling of dynamic manufacturing processes with slow drift using data-driven approaches is challenging because most data-driven models are trained by off-line data. In this paper, we propose to track slow drift of manufacturing process using an online Bayesian Auto-Regression eXogenous (ARX) model with time-variant parameters. The model parameters are trained off-line and are updated online using Bayes’ rule. To avoid frequent online model update, a Sample Importance test is proposed to screen online samples and only the sample that passes SI test is incremented to the VM model. The SI test decides the importance of the sample by collectively considering sample freshness, model prediction error and prediction uncertainty. The off-line sample selection algorithm can effectively reduce the sample redundancy in off-line DB while maintaining the model performance. To validate the effectiveness of the proposed method, Prognostics and Health Management (PHM) data challenge 2016 dataset is employed to predict material removal rate of chemical-mechanical planarization process. The validation results indicate that the proposed method outperforms existing state-of-art approaches in literature such as Just-in-Time (JIT) and deep learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
